NATNAEL HAILE

Phone: 404-918-1727 | Address: Decatur, GA, 30033 (willing to relocate)

Email:haile.natnael@natnaeldev.com LinkedIn:www.linkedin.com/in/natnael-haile-b146b41bb

Portfolio: http://natnaeldev.com/ GitHub: https://github.com/natnaelh14

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a Bachelor's Degree and 6+ years professional experience as a Registered Nurse. Proactive team player with good adaptability in dynamic environments looking for an engaging professional development. Passionate, detail- oriented, and curious developer using my skills to solve problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap | Bulma | Styled Components | JavaScript | jQuery | Node.js |

Express.js | API | JSON | AJAX | React | React Hooks | Redux | TypeScript | MySQL | Sequelize | MongoDB | Mongoose | GraphQL | Apollo | Heroku | Git | GitHub | Terminal | PWA | Unit Testing | Data Structures | Algorithms | Agile Development | Jest | GitHub Actions | Mocha |

CICD

PROJECTS

Jboard

- **Github**: https://github.com/natnaelh14/jboard
- Live Link: https://jboard-app-app.herokuapp.com/
- **Tools**: JavaScript, Node, Express, React, MongoDB, GraphQL, Styled Components, JSON Web Tokens, react-beautiful-dnd
- **Summary**: a full stack application that empowers job seekers with tools · to keep track of job applications.
- Utilized GraphQL and Apollo for data queries and mutations.
- Provided custom form error messages using Mongoose schema validation
- Integrated user authentication using JSON Web Tokens.
- Used react-beautiful-dnd npm to enable drag and drop feature. Designed an interactive user interface using React.

Get Money Smart

- **Github**: https://github.com/natnaelh14/Get Money Smart :
- Live Link: https://polar-river-76787.herokuapp.com/
- **Tools**: JavaScript, Node, Express, MySQL/Sequelize, RESTful API, CRUD operations, Handlebars.js, HTML, CSS
- **Summary**: a full stack application that simulates the functionality of a mobile bank for educational purposes.

- Utilized express-session and connect-session-sequelize to enable user authentication.
- Used Handlebars.js to dynamically generate HTML pages. Built database using MySQL and Sequelize ORM.

Empty Pantry

- **Github**: https://github.com/natnaelh14/empty-pantry
- Live Link: https://natnaelh14.github.io/empty-pantry/
- Tools: JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML
- **Summary**: a web application that lets users find recipes using ingredients they have on hand
- Utilized fetch APIs to retrieve recipe information and dynamically · generated recipe cards using jQuery
- Used local storage to save meal information based on the selected calendar day.

EXPERIENCE

Registered Nurse, Intensive Care Unit Wellstar Hospital

Aug 2019 - Present Atlanta, GA

- Delivered patient care in a dedicated COVID unit.
- Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team to ensure the desired patient outcomes.

Registered Nurse, Oncology Northside Hospital

Aug 2015 - Mar 2020 Atlanta, GA

• Served a leadership role in providing the highest quality of patient care and precepting new nurses.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology | Atlanta, GA | 2021

• Full Stack Web Development Certificate

Graceland University | Lamoni, IA | 2010 - 2014

• Bachelor of Science in Nursing

CERTIFICATION

Zero To Mastery | Udemy Course | 2021

• The Complete Web Developer Course Certificate

Zero To Mastery | Udemy Course | 2021

• JavaScript: The Advanced Concepts